♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we pass by the magnificent scenery ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Could it be that both of us
are filled with desolation? ♪
♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we lead such a life ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Turning back, you and I ♪
♪ Seize the current moment ♪
♪ The sky is painted
with a gentle pallet of pastel colors ♪
♪ Let's walk together ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ The snow in front of us ♪
♪ Will dye our hair white ♪
♪ In an instant ♪
[Joy of Life Season 2]
[Adapted from Mao Ni's Joy of Life
on Yuewen Group's Qidian platform]
[Episode 25]
Ling'er.
Ling'er, where are you?
Is she leaving so soon?
I had someone to ask your servant.
They said you like perilla soup.
My men learned
how to cook this from them.
How does it taste?
The Ye family is in charge
of the Capital's defense.
They will come looking for me
once they find out I have disappeared.
You didn't disappear.
You left the Capital
for an urgent matter
and left a letter.
What letter?
You imitated my handwriting?
She doesn't want this.
Why did you capture me?
I'm worried you would tell Wan'er
that Fan Xian is related
to Lin Gong's death.
Don't be impulsive.
You can't do this to your friend.
How could she get married
if you were to tell her that in advance?
You are the fine one to talk.
You are planning to expose this
at the wedding.
Why do you not trust me?
Why do you think?
Don't you think the strip is a bit long?
Yeah, right.
I think this piece is quite nice.
This should be of the best quality.
Best quality.
What do you think?
Not bad.
No one is asking you.
Why did you come here?
He came here for me.
He wants to speak to me.
Don't go.
I'm not in a hurry.
Go ahead.
Finish it quickly. We have to continue.
What's it?
Father sends for you.
I will go right away.
It's fine. Yours is more important.
He is not in a hurry.
But I am.
Father.
Did you ask for me?
It fits you really well.
If you say so,
I will take this.
No, I didn't say that.
What I said doesn't matter.
I can't stand it anymore.
There are so many boxes of gowns left.
You should be well-prepared
for the big event in life.
No,
I just don't see the difference
between those gowns.
Exactly.
Did you try on so many gowns back then?
Mine was more than yours.
How did you manage that?
I simply survived the torture.
Why are you sighing?
I was thinking
that ordinary people
don't have the opportunity
to try on so many gowns like you do.
Your annoyance is actually
someone else's happiness.
Did I say something wrong?
Wait,
are you really Fan Sizhe?
I actually heard that from your mouth.
I have witnessed a lot
when I traveled northward.
The Qing State
may considered a rich country,
but there are still many people
who are starving.
So?
So
I want to make more money.
I will open as many stores as possible
across the world,
like in Qing State, Northern Qi,
or even in Dongyi City.
With this wide expansion,
I can hire more people.
I didn't think it too ambitiously
or too far ahead.
I just want to make sure
everyone can fill their hunger.
Rightfully so.
Making money alone isn't enough.
You have grown mature
by giving thought to this.
Fan Xian,
here is something
you need to consider yourself.
The news of your wedding
has stirred up the entire Capital
due to your fame as the Immortal Poet
as well as
your takeover of the Imperial Treasury.
Besides,
His Majesty appointed this marriage.
All the court officials
are waiting to come
to deliver their blessings.
Our house is too small
to receive all of them.
What do you think
about the wedding guest list?
I have to remind you this.
It's easy to decide who you invite.
But those who are left out
might hold grudges
and stab you in the back.
Xian.
Convince Father
that the auction would work.
No matter who I invite or not,
it's controversial.
That's right.
If so, I will invite no one.
The wedding can't be held
without a banquet.
It's a family banquet.
Family banquet?
Bravo!
The carriage is here.
Magnificent.
The flower carriage is beautiful.
The flower carriage is here.
So beautifully decorated.
The flower carriage is coming this way.
What a flower carriage.
So beautiful.
It's fragrant.
[Fan's Residence]
Little Xian!
- Over there!
- Slow down.
It's really coming.
The big thing over there
is so beautiful.
They all say it's coming for you.
Do you know that?
I will go check it out for you.
Do they spread the petals
all the way from Xinyang to here?
Day and night. Night and day.
Without rest?
They work in shifts.
The flower petals must be a lot.
Can the carriage carry so much?
They pluck petals
along the way.
I wonder how many mountains
have become bare.
I chucked her out of the Capital,
yet she returns here publicly
bearing gifts for me.
After all, she's Princess Lin's mother.
I doubt
if she would be so kind.
It's here.
It's coming.
It's coming. Hurry.
Look at those fresh flowers.
So lovely.
Magnificent.
Look at this.
I have never seen something like this.
It smells great.
So fragrant.
Who made this?
I haven't seen one in my dream.
It's my first time.
What does it mean?
It has been a long while.
You are grounded in Xinyang.
You shouldn't return here
without a decree.
I defied the decree.
I came back here secretly.
Report me now.
I'm sure it works.
Why did you come back to the Capital?
This is for you.
Don't be afraid.
This is a wedding gift from me.
[Imperial Treasury Ledgers]
You are going to take over
the Imperial Treasury
after marrying Wan'er.
Are these the ledgers
of the Imperial Treasury?
It's a sincere gift, isn't it?
Did you defy the decree and return here
just for this?
On your wedding day,
I wish to see Wan'er.
She is my daughter.
The wedding is the biggest day for her.
I have never lived a life like hers,
but I hope she does.
Besides, I want to leave her
with the best memories.
So during the wedding,
I call a truce.
And after the wedding?
What a question.
The fierce fight resumes.
Have you ever considered
that I said no?
Like I said,
you can report me.
I only want to do what I want.
Whatever your choice is,
I'm ready for it.
How long will you stay?
It depends on my mood.
Where do you stay?
Not the Fan's Residence, anyway.
Get yourself a good hiding spot.
You should call me "mother",
shouldn't you?
Read slowly.
Don't read in bright light.
Just take your time.
[In the 61st year of the Qing,
in debt of 730,000 taels.]
[In the 62nd year of the Qing,
in debt of 670,000 taels]
I'm good.
I finished it.
What's your read on this?
The establishment
of the Imperial Treasury
is an irreplicable legend.
After all, it was once
the greatest enterprise in the world.
You could confidently say
it's the greatest enterprise ever
in history.
What a brilliant idea
to branch out worldwide
and secure support
from the royal family.
But now it appears
to have over 20 million taels of debt.
Li Yunrui should be executed
for having messed up this business.
It's not easy to kill a royal, though.
Aren't you surprised by this debt?
I should've predicted this.
Even without any existing debt,
it would incur great debt
when handed over to me.
To you,
[Come and meet me instantly]
these aren't just ledgers,
but also a trap.
Even so,
I will fall into it
only after the wedding.
You are right.
The wedding is
the most important matter now.
Your mother also
looked forward to this day.
Should I hide these ledgers
for the time being?
I doubt it.
She arrived in the sight of all.
You should act frankly.
Frankly?
Inform the Eight Division
to copy these ledgers.
It's also time
to make good use
of your mother's invention.
[Eighth Division, Seventh Division]
To whom should we present
the copies afterward?
Anyone who needs to see them.
The Imperial Treasury
is far from a deficit.
Plus, Fan Xian has a brain on him.
I guess the shortfall could be covered
in four to five years.
The ledgers were delivered here
so openly
that those who are concerned
have been alerted.
Merchants
only pursue profits.
Since they know about the debt,
no one would dare
to do business with Fan Xian.
The shortfall
will snowball.
If nothing is done within six months,
he will have to give up
on the Imperial Treasury.
Filling up 20 million taels
in six months
is beyond what an immortal could do.
Unless
someone helps him.
After Fan Xian entered the Capital,
did he offer his service
to you?
Not yet.
You may use this debt
as a term.
It's not too much to ask, right?
You can save his life.
Only a few will save you,
but many will hit you when you are down.
After all, the figure is enormous.
Are both of your eyes unable
to read well?
No, only this.
It's presbyopia.
Aren't you worried
about the debt at all?
I'm not going to think about it
until my wedding is over.
Don't worry.
Regarding the debt,
His Majesty is aware of it. So am I.
I have no worries.
In fact, I didn't come here
only for this.
Wang Qinian told me
about the serial killer.
Did you find out who the murderer is?
I thought you would come that day.
I don't think
this can be discussed openly.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have tasked
Wang Qinian with that
instead of me.
You have the potential
to be an official.
Was it done by Mr. Wuzhu?
I don't know.
This person killed all his way
from Jiangnan to the Capital.
Whoever saw his face was killed.
Did anything happen these days?
The Capital has been peaceful
for the past few days.
It seems the murderer has disappeared.
If so, it wouldn't be him.
Wuzhu has forgotten many things.
What if this were to happen again
and he forgot you
and even attacked you?
What would you do?
I will figure something out
to treat your eyesight.
What would you do
if it's really him?
Will you come to my wedding?
It's your family banquet.
That's why I'm inviting you.
I have long lost my family.
You have me, no?
We will figure something out
after the wedding.
Is this a wedding gift?
I can't go without gifts,
can I?
What's inside? So secretive.
I wish you a happy
and everlasting marriage.
What a beauty.
Mother.
Sit still.
Let me groom you today.
When did you come back here?
I returned secretly.
Without His Majesty's decree?
No.
You are defying the order.
Does that even bother me?
But this is a serious crime.
I don't care.
If I didn't come back
on your wedding day,
that would be a more serious crime.
Mother.
There is one thing
I'm sure of in my life.
What's that?
I'm the most beautiful woman
that ever walked the earth.
Though someone is blind
and can't see me,
that's not my problem.
Who are you talking about?
Never mind that.
What I'm trying
to tell you is,
I must come to the Capital
to groom you personally.
In this world,
if I allow someone else
to be prettier than me,
it must be you.
It must be today.
Since infancy,
you have been all alone
and unhappy.
Nothing can be done
to compensate you even now.
But today,
please let me do my duty as a mother.
Let me see you
to the next journey of your life.
Mother.
No tears.
The makeup looks just perfect on you.
Mother.
Could you please stop fighting
with Fan Xian?
Look at you.
So beautiful.
You are prettier than me, my daughter.
I have done
what I have to do.
Where are you going?
I came here secretly,
so I must leave secretly.
Wan'er,
I haven't lived a life like yours.
I envy you.
Stop right there.
From today on,
forget me
completely.
I'm so glad
that you came.
Where are you going?
Where else could I go?
Leave them alone.
I don't want you to worry,
so you are coming with me.
I can't fight.
If anything happens,
I'm all yours.
Why are all the horses here?
Go that way.
Park the carriage over there.
Misters, would you mind
moving your horses forward?
All the carriages should be over there.
Go that way.
Misters,
please take the horses
over there.
Thank you so much.
Look at the grandeur.
Exactly.
How grand.
It must be someone important.
It must be.
Impressive.
Right.
What a grandeur.
Greetings, Your Highness.
He's the Crown Prince.
You are...
Wang Qinian.
Those who carry gifts, come with me.
I know what you are going to say.
This is a family banquet.
No need to follow me.
Who has arrived?
- Move!
- Well...
Move!
Clear the way!
An urgent missive from Northern Qi.
[Imperial Edict]
Urgent missive from the border army!
Did Northern Qi intrude on the border?
No, it doesn't concern the warfare.
It's a letter for Mr. Fan
from Northern Qi.
Is it appropriate
to send a private letter
on an urgent delivery?
The sender is
the Emperor of Northern Qi.
There's no way the groom
is serving us the liquor.
Do away with formalities
in the family banquet.
What's wrong?
I'm the groom.
Why are you more nervous?
Fan.
Come with me.
Is Miss Ruoruo in?
Why?
You have already gotten drunk
before even drinking.
News from the palace says
my wedding with Ruoruo
is right after your wedding.
Ruoruo won't marry you.
Fan Xian,
this is the imperial decree.
It doesn't matter
whether or not Ruoruo and I want it.
But she doesn't want to marry you.
Is she trying
to defy the decree, then?
To be honest,
I have always liked Ruoruo.
Why don't we try to get along?
You know what I am like.
What about Yuan Meng?
Yuan Meng...
Yuan Meng
is only a silly past.
I'm not involved
in the Baoyue Pleasure House at all.
I believe you,
and I forgave you.
But Ruoruo won't marry you.
No one can defy
the marriage appointed by His Majesty.
Congratulations!
Your Highness.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Chengru.
Well,
carry the things to the yard.
Don't touch any bizarre thing
you see there.
Did you hear me?
I just came here
to have a drink with my brothers.
That thing,
is it fixed?
Yes, it's fixed.
The little emperor of Northern Qi
wrote you a letter.
Take a look at it.
Mr. Fan.
He is demanding updates.
What does that mean?
This little emperor enjoys
reading "Red Mansion".
He only mentioned this in it?
There are more.
You may read it yourself.
One of the Four Grandmasters, Ku He,
intends to take
Ruoruo as his "closed door" disciple.
[*Last disciple]
Isn't Haitang Duoduo
his "closed door" disciple?
It says here,
"The door isn't fully shut,
so he's closing it again."
Does that even make a reason?
The our Grandmasters
are exceptionally skilled,
their thoughts are extraordinary.
Deliver it to the palace
for His Majesty to decide.
I will see to that now.
Well,
please take a seat.
Fan.
How did you manage this?
Do you think
this marriage will continue?
If the Four Grandmasters are involved,
I'm afraid this marriage
won't proceed as planned.
With the Four Grandmasters
above the monarch,
do you think this is a good sign?
But it has been the fact.
I was just saying.
Don't take it too seriously.
Hurry and take a seat.
The cold dishes will be served soon.
Why is the street empty?
Exactly.
Why, indeed?
You don't have to hold my hand.
Xie Bi'an isn't here.
I can only rely on you
if assassins show up.
I'm only at ease
when I hold your hand.
I will protect you.
But do keep your word,
don't ruin Wan'er's wedding.
If you can't believe me,
kill me, then.
Look, I'm all alone
and don't have martial arts skills.
You can easily
kill me.
If you talk nonsense during the wedding,
I will kill you.
That's a deal, then.
What deal?
Either you protect me
or kill me.
My life
is in your hands now.
Now that you have married Wan'er,
we are considered relatives.
We are one family now.
Chengru, to be honest with you,
I'm so worried about him
that I can't sleep for nights.
What should we do
about the debt of the Imperial Treasury?
Surely, you are merciful.
One more thing.
I can see that Northern Qi
regards you highly.
But then, the deep debt
is our own state affair.
We can't fill up the hole
with money from another state.
This is a big no.
Don't overthink, Your Highness.
Even though this little emperor
loves "Red Mansion",
he won't pay the debt
of over 20 million.
No one in this universe
would demand updates like this.
True, though.
Speaking of which,
what should we do about the debt?
Today's Fan Xian's wedding.
Let's not get into this.
All right, let's drop it.
One more word.
Fortunately, that fellow is grounded.
I can't image how trouble it could be
if he comes.
Mr. Fan,
the Second Prince has come.
[Fan's Residence]
Luckily, I came without guards.
Otherwise, they couldn't fit it here.
He is not like you.
He's afraid of dying.
I'm afraid of dying too,
but that's not my greatest fear.
What's your greatest fear, then?
I fear
an uneventful situation.
It's boring.
You're unbelievable.
Mr. Fan
invites you in.
Today is a big day.
Everyone is welcome.
That's wonderful.
I was worried he might shut me out.
Please come in, Your Highness.
Everyone is here.
Greetings, Your Highness.
No need for that, Chengze.
You didn't bow.
You see,
Chengze came personally
for Fan Xian's wedding.
You are indeed all heart.
But if His Majesty reprimands you
for having defied his decree,
we brothers
will bear it with you.
Are you talking about the confinement?
I asked for his permission.
What...
I requested
a decree
to attend Wan'er's wedding.
That's great.
I was worried for nothing.
My bad.
I shall drink to that.
Me too.
Well, what do you know?
Such brotherhood does exist.
Your wedding gift.
Thank you.
Open it.
I prepared jewels at first.
But I thought
you had lots of those at home.
So I chose something more direct.
500,000 taels.
This is too much.
This barely makes a dent
in the 20 million debt.
I'm so worried for you.
You two are truly brothers.
Pardon?
His Highness was worried for me too.
I can never compare
to His Highness' compassion.
Let's talk about the real business.
You have a lot of things to take care of
after taking over the Imperial Treasury.
You need to venture into business.
But it won't be easy for me
due to the debt.
Don't worry.
I have contacts
with many merchant families.
They will humor me
and offer help.
Indeed.
Chengze has a good intention.
I sense a but.
Merchants
are profit-driven.
If you take advantage of them now,
how are you going to deal
with them later?
If everyone meddles
in the Imperial Treasury,
it will be troublesome.
That being said,
Chengze is different
from those profit-driven merchants.
Of course he bears a good will.
You have a good assessment of people.
But we can't let
the Imperial Treasury be ruined
in the hands of Mr. Fan.
Exactly.
How could we not help
our brother-in-law?
Even blood brothers
want to kill each other.
Your Highness,
do you plan to cover the debt?
If I could afford 20 million taels,
this would be a trouble.
Why did you even bring this up, then?
If you have time
tomorrow or the day after,
come to my residence.
We can think of solutions.
Wonderful.
From then on, the Imperial Inspectorate
and the Imperial Treasury
will be in your pocket.
Chengze, this is no joke.
I wouldn't dare fraternize
with officials
like you do.
You should consider me too.
You don't have to serve me.
This is just favor trading between us.
Yes, favors trading
could bring endless threats.
It's better than being a lackey.
Oops, it slipped again.
I just keep one.
50,000 taels will cost me
at least seven impeachments
from the Imperial Procuratorate.
Don't jinx me on my big day.
Your Highness,
have you heard of "honeymoon"?
Is that a dessert or something?
No.
It means
Wan'er and I will be on a hiatus
after the wedding
without any official business.
I appreciate your offer,
but I won't visit
the Eastern Palace.
How do you plan
to clear the debt without help?
I don't want to talk about this
on such a fine day.
Gentlemen,
today is my first time
doing the wedding ritual.
The auspicious hour is arriving soon.
Why don't you all join us
for the ceremony?
The auspicious hour has arrived!
Shouldn't the matchmaker
be holding this?
I insisted.
I must witness this important moment.
Bonding twain hearts with a tie,
and they shall never part.
Wan'er, I want to tell you something.
Young Master,
you can tell her
when the ritual is over.
No.
I must say it now.
Wan'er.
There is something
Father wants me to tell you
on your wedding day.
What's it about?
He wants
you
to look after Dabao.
All right.
I will.
I'm done.
Very good.
I'm done!
Yay! I'm done!
Dabao is done.
Yay!
All right.
Shall we start?
♪ The youth raises his head ♪
♪ As he moves toward his moon ♪
♪ People tease him for being delusional ♪
♪ Wondering why he is so unconventional ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ How could it remain unstained? ♪
♪ If silver tael has a value ♪
♪ Who can truly be carefree? ♪
♪ All of you are right ♪
♪ He said: "Please" ♪
♪ "Make way" ♪
♪ "Let me drink until I drop" ♪
♪ On the court ♪
♪ I recite several verses ♪
♪ Let me wear a white robe ♪
♪ And cross the alley
filled with insanity ♪
♪ To scoop up the moon's reflection
in the muddy pond ♪
♪ Sirs, please forgive me ♪
♪ Your words of advice ♪
♪ I understand,
but I don't want to pretend ♪
♪ People search for the golden land ♪
♪ While I search for the moon ♪
♪ Why should we travel together? ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ Remarkably worldly-wise
yet hopelessly romantic ♪
♪ Know what you love ♪
♪ Don't change ♪
♪ If one has witnessed
both light and shadow ♪
♪ Yet retains their innocence ♪
♪ They shall be cloaked in moonlight ♪
♪ As they journey through the night ♪